Vague authority figure, maybe.
Don't worry, I said. They'll be fine. Your kids
will remember you as perfect in every way.
They didn't have time to grow contemptuous of you.
Your wife will cry on the outside, but will be
secretly relieved. To be fair, your marriage
was falling apart. If it's any consolation,
she'll feel very guilty for feeling relieved.
Oh. So what happens now?
Do I go to heaven or hell or something?
Neither. You'll be reincarnated.
Ah. So the Hindus were
right. All religions are right in their own way.
Walk with me. You followed along
as we strode through the void. Where are we
going? Nowhere in particular. It's just nice to walk while
we talk. So what's the point,
then? When I get reborn, I'll just be a blank slate,
right? A baby.
So all my experiences and everything, everything I did
in this life won't matter? Not so. You have
within you all the knowledge and experiences of
all your past lives. You just don't remember them right now.
I stopped walking and took you by the should.
Your soul is more magnificent, beautiful and
gigantic than you can possibly imagine. A human
mind can only contain a tiny fraction of what you are.
It's like sticking your finger in a glass of water to see
if it's hot or cold. You put a tiny part of yourself into
the vessel, and when you bring it back out, you've gained
all the experiences it had. You've been in a human for the
last 48 years.